[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "name": "Bulbasaur",
    "type": ["grass", "poison"],

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/bulbasaur.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/bulbasaur.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 45,
      "attack": 49,
      "defense": 49
    },
    "moves": [
      { "move": "tackle", "level": 1 },
      { "move": "vineWhip", "level": 3 }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "name": "Ivysaur",
    "type": ["grass", "poison"],

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/ivysaur.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/ivysaur.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 60,
      "attack": 62,
      "defense": 63
    },
    "moves": [
      { "move": "tackle", "level": 1 },
      { "move": "vineWhip", "level": 1 }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "name": "Venusaur",
    "type": ["grass", "poison"],

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/venusaur.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/venusaur.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 80,
      "attack": 82,
      "defense": 83
    },
    "moves": [
      { "move": "tackle", "level": 1 },
      { "move": "vineWhip", "level": 1 }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "name": "Charmander",
    "type": "fire",

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/charmander.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/charmander.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 39,
      "attack": 52,
      "defense": 43
    },
    "moves": [
      { "move": "scratch", "level": 1 },
      { "move": "ember", "level": 4 }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "name": "Charmeleon",
    "type": "fire",

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/charmeleon.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/charmeleon.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 58,
      "attack": 64,
      "defense": 58
    },
    "moves": [
      { "move": "scratch", "level": 1 },
      { "move": "ember", "level": 1 }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "name": "Charizard",
    "type": ["fire", "flying"],

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/charizard.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/charizard.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 78,
      "attack": 84,
      "defense": 78
    },
    "moves": [
      { "move": "scratch", "level": 1 },
      { "move": "ember", "level": 1 }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "name": "Squirtle",
    "type": "water",

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/squirtle.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/squirtle.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 44,
      "attack": 48,
      "defense": 65
    },
    "moves": [
      { "move": "tackle", "level": 1 },
      { "move": "waterGun", "level": 3 }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "name": "Wartortle",
    "type": "water",

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/wartortle.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/wartortle.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 59,
      "attack": 63,
      "defense": 80
    },
    "moves": [
      { "move": "tackle", "level": 1 },
      { "move": "waterGun", "level": 1 }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "name": "Blastoise",
    "type": "water",

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/blastoise.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/blastoise.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 79,
      "attack": 83,
      "defense": 100
    },
    "moves": [
      { "move": "tackle", "level": 1 },
      { "move": "waterGun", "level": 1 }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "name": "Caterpie",
    "type": "bug",

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/caterpie.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/caterpie.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 45,
      "attack": 30,
      "defense": 35
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "tackle", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "name": "Metapod",
    "type": "bug",

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/metapod.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/metapod.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 50,
      "attack": 20,
      "defense": 55
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "tackle", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "name": "Butterfree",
    "type": ["bug", "flying"],

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/butterfree.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/butterfree.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 60,
      "attack": 45,
      "defense": 50
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "tackle", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "name": "Weedle",
    "type": ["bug", "poison"],

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/weedle.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/weedle.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 40,
      "attack": 35,
      "defense": 30
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "poisonSting", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "name": "Kakuna",
    "type": ["bug", "poison"],

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/kakuna.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/kakuna.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 45,
      "attack": 25,
      "defense": 50
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "poisonSting", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "name": "Beedrill",
    "type": ["bug", "poison"],

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/beedrill.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/beedrill.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 65,
      "attack": 90,
      "defense": 40
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "poisonSting", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "name": "Pidgey",
    "type": ["normal", "flying"],

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/pidgey.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/pidgey.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 40,
      "attack": 45,
      "defense": 40
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "tackle", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "name": "Pidgeotto",
    "type": ["normal", "flying"],

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/pidgeotto.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/pidgeotto.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 63,
      "attack": 60,
      "defense": 55
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "tackle", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "name": "Pidgeot",
    "type": ["normal", "flying"],

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/pidgeot.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/pidgeot.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 83,
      "attack": 80,
      "defense": 75
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "tackle", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "name": "Rattata",
    "type": "normal",

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/rattata.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/rattata.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 30,
      "attack": 56,
      "defense": 35
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "tackle", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "name": "Raticate",
    "type": "normal",

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/raticate.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/raticate.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 55,
      "attack": 81,
      "defense": 60
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "tackle", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "name": "Spearow",
    "type": ["normal", "flying"],

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/spearow.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/spearow.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 40,
      "attack": 60,
      "defense": 30
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "peck", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "name": "Fearow",
    "type": ["normal", "flying"],

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/fearow.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/fearow.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 65,
      "attack": 90,
      "defense": 65
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "peck", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "name": "Ekans",
    "type": "poison",

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/ekans.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/ekans.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 35,
      "attack": 60,
      "defense": 44
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "poisonSting", "level": 4 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "name": "Arbok",
    "type": "poison",

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/arbok.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/arbok.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 60,
      "attack": 95,
      "defense": 69
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "poisonSting", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "name": "Pikachu",
    "type": "electric",

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/pikachu.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/pikachu.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 35,
      "attack": 55,
      "defense": 40
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "quickAttack", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "name": "Raichu",
    "type": "electric",

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/raichu.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/raichu.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 60,
      "attack": 90,
      "defense": 55
    },
    "moves": [{ "move": "quickAttack", "level": 1 }]
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "name": "Sandshrew",
    "type": "ground",

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/sandshrew.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/sandshrew.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 50,
      "attack": 75,
      "defense": 85
    },
    "moves": [
      { "move": "scratch", "level": 1 },
      { "move": "poisonSting", "level": 3 }
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "name": "Sandslash",
    "type": "ground",

    "sprites": {
      "back": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/back-normal/sandslash.gif",
      "front": "https://img.pokemondb.net/sprites/black-white/anim/normal/sandslash.gif"
    },
    "baseStats": {
      "hp": 75,
      "attack": 100,
      "defense": 110
    },
    "moves": [
      { "move": "scratch", "level": 1 },
      { "move": "poisonSting", "level": 1 }
    ]
  }
]
